ZIKANG (KHAN) ZHENG

Singapore|Beijing, China ♦ (+65)9376-1147 ♦ zikangzheng@gmail.com/e1323314@u.nus.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strong interest in corporate strategy, particularly in the innovation and technology company. About 3 years of experience in AI/Finance/Consulting companies involving product management, full-stack coding, UI/UX and Business/data analytic. Project experience in product strategy regarding new features in artificial intelligence chatbot, and another in developing the Finance system in the University housing & finance system. As a product manager, I have realized the importance of corporate strategy in guiding the team and addressing market and user needs, and my product experience aligns well with corporate strategy roles, given their shared focus on shaping the company's future.

CORE COMPETENCE

- Team Management & Leadership
- Entrepreneurship Strategy
- Product Ownership
- Communication & Responsibility
- Fast Learner

- Product & Prototype Design (Adobe CC, Figma, XD, Miro)
- Modeling (AutoCAD, Sketchup)
- Design Thinking
- Openness to Learning

- Programming (Python, PHP, JS, HTML, CSS, C++, C, R & Java, Unity)
- DataBase (Oracle, MySQL, PL/SQL)
- Data Analysis (Excel, Matlab, SSRS)
- Problem Solving

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Engineer Design and Innovation, 01/2024 - 12/2024

National University of Singapore - Singapore

• Relevant Courses: Entrepreneurship Strategy, Venture Capital Funding, Design Strategies & Leadership, Design Thinking & Product Development, Creativity & Problem-Solving

Bachelor of Science: Mathematical Science, 07/2016 - 05/2021

University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

- Academic Accolades: Outstanding International Student, Go Global Structured Undergraduate Research
- Relevant Courses: Computer Graphics, Digital Media Design, SQL Databases, Human Computer Interaction, Machine Learning & Data Mining, Computer Hardware & Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence

Professional Experience

AIGC Product Manager Internship, 11/2023 - 01/2024

Jieyue Xingchen - Beijing, China

- Directed and Managed a team of 30 employees in creating the AI risk management platform and Collaborated with UX researcher, marketing specialist, and programming team.
- Conducted mid-month report in other competitor products by industry research report, social media search, and store search & app trials.
- Conceptualised a distinctive storytelling product strategy that highlights unique features within the Large Language Model market.
- Hosted the user interview and analysed target users and identified the target users and the demand.

The University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

Internship, 01/2020 - 08/2020

Part Time, 09/2020 - 07/2021

Program Analyst Full Time, 08/2021 - 08/2023

- Developed and launched integrated systems for meal plans, finances, and housing systems using JQuery and PHP in Yii Framework Increased operational efficiency and improved user satisfaction for over 55,000 students and staff.
- Orchestrated the UI/UX design process using Adobe Photoshop and Figma and enhanced product adoption rates.
- Programmed a robust PL/SQL to manage Oracle database by building schema views, packages and Oracle form builder. Optimised database performance, significantly reducing data retrieval times and increasing reliability.
- Developed SSRS reports to support finance and accounting operations; Enhanced financial decision-making through accurate reporting.
- Executed system-level testing to ensure performance standards to assure high-quality software releases.

Information Technology Department Internship, 09/2019 - 12/2019

Pythian - Ottawa, Canada

- Delivered comprehensive hardware and software support using customer ticketing systems including JIRA, JIRA
 Service Desk and Slack to end-users, and achieved a consistent track record of high user satisfaction and swift
 resolution of IT inquiries, reinforcing the company's commitment to excellence in client service.
- Crafted and deployed the company's internal website utilising Confluence, JavaScript, HTML and CSS for optimal functionality and user engagement and workflow processes, enhancing operational efficiency within the company.
- Delivered customer assistance regarding hardware and software malfunctions. Preserved high satisfaction ratings through diligent service and effective problem resolution.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Project Happraisal | UBC SPIN Lab, 03/2023 - 09/2023

• Designed Figma prototype for the WearOS application interface, and designed IOT robot prototype. Implemented Python Websocket server and data processing and data mining. Designed the circuit Arduino ESP32 robot and Implemented code in Arduino IDE. Participated in research regarding haptic technology and emotional release therapy.

Visual Graph Comparison | Supervisor: Professor Kuijper, 05/2019 to 12/2019

- Conducted research into factors influencing perception of differences between graphs; used screen-capturing technologies and thinking-aloud protocols paired with qualitative content analysis to identify several contributing factors including edge crossings, shape and symmetry based on research participant observations.
- Analysed participants' comments and identified methods to improve research methodologies; determined 8 influencing factors of graphical perception: symmetry, shape, edge crossing, density, white space, number of layers, groups and arrowheads

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Third Person game COVID-Omega | BC Game Jam 2022 (MAP, Audio/SFX & UI Developer), 09/2022

- Collaborated with a team of 7 participants to ideate, develop and launch pandemic-style game titled *Covid-Omega*. Fostered a dynamic team environment and enhanced digital entertainment options during the pandemic.
- Produced Unity and Unreal Engine to design game map and user interface; employed SFX for audio implementation and developed C# scripts for the game's blueprint with a robust and intuitive interface and great gaming experience.
- Project Link: https://ventOs.itch.io/covid-omega

Hi.re Project | UQ Virtual Hackathon, 07/2020

• Led a team of 8 through the development of a web project using JavaScript, React, HTML & CSS. Delivered a web application in charity, showcasing effective team collaboration in a competitive environment.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google UX Design Professional Certificate | Google

Business Strategy Specialization Certificate | *University of Virginia*

Introduction to Marketing Certificate | Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania

Successful Negotiation: Essential Strategies & Skills Certificate | University of Michigan

Conflict Management Specialization Certificate | University of California, Irvine

Green Economy & Trade Certificate | UN Institute for Training & Research & Partnership for Action on Green Economy

The Materiality of ESG Factors Certificate | Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania

Introduction to Psychology Certificate | Yale University

INTERESTS & LINKS

Interests | Kyudo (Japanese Archery), Photography
GitHub Link | github.com/khan123451 | Personal Portfolio | www.khanzheng.com